Mathis Petrovich







Email:

mathis.petrovich
@enpc.fr

Github:

Phone: (+33)6 66 65 84 19

in LinkedIn:

mathis-petrovich

Mathis Petrovich

PhD Student - Controllable human motion synthesis

Summary I am an ELLIS PhD student at the École des Ponts (ENPC) in the computer vision team IMAGINE (LIGM, École des Ponts, Univ Gustave Eiffel, CNRS) and at the Max Planck Institute for Intelligent Systems (MPI) in the Perceiving Systems department. I am advised by both Gül Varol (ENPC) and Michael J. Black (MPI). My PhD topic is to generate realistic and diverse human body motion in a controllable way (given labels or text instructions). I am interested in a lot of area of research, from optimal transport, kernel methods to image processing, computer vision and human motions.

Positions

2020 - present : PhD student, LIGM (ENPC) - Perceiving Systems (MPI)

Subject: Controllable human motion synthesis via generative models

Advisors: Gül Varol and Michael J. Black

Location: France/Germany

2019 - 2020 : Research Intern, RIKEN AIP, University of Kyoto 9 months

Subject: Machine learning and optimal transport

Advisor: Makoto Yamada

Location: Japan

2019: Research Intern, DxO Labs 6 months

Subject: Semantic segmentation and image matting

Advisor: Wolf Hauser **Location:** France

2018: Research Intern, Carnegie Mellon University 5 months

Subject: Object tracking in videos

Advisor: Martial Hebert **Location:** United States

2017: Research Intern, LIF 2 months

Subject: Correction strategy for natual language parser

Advisor: Alexis Nasr **Location:** France

Education

2016 - 2020 : École Normale Supérieure (ENS) Paris-Saclay, MSc Paris, France

Research engineering school, theoretical and applied computer science

2018 - 2019 : ENS Paris-Saclay, Master 2 Paris, France

Master MVA: machine learning and computer vision

2017 - 2018 : ENS Paris-Saclay, Master 1 Paris, France

Master of research in theoretical computer science (MPRI)

2016 - 2017 : Diderot University, Bachelor degree Paris, France

Theoretical computer science

2014 - 2016 : Lycée Masséna Nice, France

Preparation course for exams to enter French engineering schools

2011 - 2014 : Lycée Saint-Louis Gignac-la-Nerthe, France

High School Diploma (Baccalauréat) with highest honours, specialised in Sciences

Mathis Petrovich





Email:

mathis.petrovich @enpc.fr

Website:

m.petrovich.fr

O Github: Mathux

\C Phone : (+33)666658419

in LinkedIn:

mathis-petrovich

Research Experience

Publications

- o 2022, ECCV: Mathis Petrovich, Michael J. Black, Gül Varol TEMOS: Generating diverse human motions from textual descriptions.
- o 2021, ICCV: Mathis Petrovich, Michael J. Black, Gül Varol ACTOR: Action-Conditioned 3D Human Motion Synthesis with Transformer VAE.
- o 2022, ECML: Mathis Petrovich*, Chao Liang*, Ryoma Sato, Yanbin Liu, Yao-Hung Hubert Tsai, Linchao Zhu, Yi Yang, Ruslan Salakhutdinov, Makoto Yamada FROT: Feature Robust Optimal Transport for High-dimensional Data.
- o 2020, MLCB: Dinesh Singh, Héctor Climente-González, Mathis Petrovich, Eiryo Kawakami, Makoto Yamada

FsNet: Feature Selection Network on High-dimensional Biological Data.

- o 2020, arXiv: Mathis Petrovich, Makoto Yamada FALL: Fast local linear regression with anchor regularization.
- o 2020, ICMEW: Abhishek Goswami, Mathis Petrovich, Wolf Hauser, Frederic Dufaux

Tone Mapping Operators: Progressing Towards Semantic-Awareness.

Reviewing

- o IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI) 2022
- European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) 2022
- Computers & Graphics 2021

Teaching

- o 2021 2022 : ENS Paris-Saclay, Teaching Assistant, M2 (Master MVA) Object recognition and computer vision (RecVis)
- o 2020 2021 : ENPC, Course Instructor, L3 (Bachelor) C++ teaching

Open-source repositories

Mathux/TEMOS

115 3 ₺

↑ Mathux/ACTOR

202 🛊 27 ¥

- Mathux/FROT
- Mathux/FALL

Talks in Conferences and Invited Talk



2022

TEMOS: Generating diverse human motions from textual descriptions.

- o ENPC Retreat, La Turballe, France, tutorial Tips and tricks for PhD Students
- **♣ A3SI, France**, PhD students' seminar TEMOS: Generating diverse human motions from textual descriptions.

2021

• **ICCV**, Virtual, poster

ACTOR: Action-Conditioned 3D Human Motion Synthesis with Transformer VAE.

• ELLIS Doctoral Symposium, Germany, poster

ACTOR: Action-Conditioned 3D Human Motion Synthesis with Transformer VAE.

• **Priken AIP, Kyoto University**, Virtual, invited talk

ACTOR: Action-Conditioned 3D Human Motion Synthesis with Transformer VAE. • **MSTIC doctoral school**, Virtual, Doctoral day

ACTOR: Action-Conditioned 3D Human Motion Synthesis with Transformer VAE.

Mathis Petrovich







∠ Email:

mathis.petrovich
@enpc.fr

Website:

m.petrovich.fr

Github:

C Phone: (+33)6 66 65 84 19

in LinkedIn:
mathis-petrovich

Skills, Interests and Personal

Machine learning

- Deep learning
- Generative models
- Human body models
- Optimal transport
- Local linear regression

Computer skills

- o 🥏 Python
- **③** C++
- OCaml
- slurm (working on a cluster)
- ssh (working on a server)
- o 🞧 Git
- 🐧 Linux
- o MEX
- o **l** Blender

Deep Learning Stack

- o O PyTorch
- PyTorch Lightning
- # Hydra
- **1** TensorBoard
- Weights & Biases

Languages

- **I French:** Native speaker
- **English:** C1 Level (IELTS Band 7)
- **German:** Basic Level

International experience

- **2022-2023:** Tübingen, Germany
- **2019-2020:** Kyoto, Japan
- o 2018: Pittsburgh, US

Personal interests

- Rubik's cube
- Magic tricks
- Hiking
- Home automation

Soft skills

- Fast Learner
- Communication
- Problem solving
- Entreprenarial spirit
- Curious
- Creative